在本节中，我想谈谈机器人和工作。每当我去公开场合
In this section I'd like to talk about robots and jobs. Whenever I go and give a public
谈论机器人技术，观众中的某个人总是问我机器人和工作。Arn't
talk about robotics, somebody in the audience always ask me about robots and jobs. Arn’t
机器人会把人从工作中拿走？确实如此，机器人将把工作带走
robots going to take jobs away from people? And it's true, robots will take jobs away
来自人民。但我相信人们不应该做的工作。那是因为那些
from people. But there are jobs that I believe people shouldn't do. And that's because those
工作很危险。
jobs are dangerous.
因此，如果我们查看此处显示的数据，我们会查看每100,000人的死亡人数
So if we look at the data shown here, we look at the number of fatalities per a 100,000
在2个时间点记录了许多不同职业领域的工人。和我们
workers in a number of different occupational areas recorded at 2 points in time. And we
可以看到有一些行业真的很危险。人们可以去
can see that there are some industries, which are really quite dangerous. People can go
在其中一个行业工作，晚上不回家，因为他们已经被杀了
to work in one of these industries and not come home at night because they've been killed
在工作中。而对我来说这是不可接受的。如果有危险的工作，那就应该
on the job. And to me that's non-acceptable. If there are dangerous jobs, then it should
是机器而不是人类。
be machines doing work instead of humans.
我将重点关注采矿业，因为这是我花费更多的一个领域
I'm going to focus a bit on the mining industry because that's an area where I spent more
10年来开发用于地下和露天采矿的各种机器人技术。
than 10 years developing various robotic technologies for underground and surface mining.
让我们首先看看美国采矿业编制的一些死亡数据
Let's first of all look at some fatality data from the United States mining industry compiled
在大约100年的时间里。
over a period of about 100 years.
线图显示了按生产标准化的死亡率。然后我们看到一个非常愉快的减少
The line graph show the fatality rate normalized to production. Then we see a very happy reduction
在那个死亡率。黑线是煤炭行业，红线是
in that fatality rate. The black line is for the coal industry and the red line is for
非煤炭工业，一般是服务采矿业务。他们往往更安全
non-coal industry which is generally service mining operations. They tend to be safer than
地下采煤。
underground coal mining.
因此，随着时间的推移，已经有了相当大的改进。我们一如既往地观察
So while there has been a very considerable improvement over time. We observe just as
我们为道路交通事故造成的死亡率提高了稳定性
we did for road accident fatalities that the rate of improvement is plateauing and it's
没有平稳到零。它的平稳值高于零。所以有一些残余
not plateauing to zero. It's plateauing to a value above zero. So there is some residual
采矿作业中将发生的死亡率。
rate of fatality that will occur in mining operations.
尽管经过了100年的持续改进，我们仍然在努力争取这一速度
Despite 100 years of continuous improvement, we are really struggling to get this rate
降到零。如果我们看看今天矿山发生的事故类型，我们就会看到
down to zero. If we look at the types of accidents that occur in mines today, we see that the
课程真的很多样化。其中一些是人类之间的不幸遭遇
courses are really quite varied. Some of them are unfortunate encounters between human beings
和机器，输送带和卡车等。其中一些是触电，人
and machines, conveyer belts and trucks and so on. Some of them are electrocutions, people
滑倒和摔倒，相对较少的人涉及人们被落石杀死，
slipping and falling, relatively few of them involved people being killed by falling rocks,
这也许是大多数人认为在地下矿井中导致死亡的原因。
which is perhaps what most people would consider to be leading cause of death in an underground mine.
那么我们能做些什么呢？重要的是将人类从危险中移除
So what can we do about this? Well the important thing is to remove the human beings from hazardous
的情况。如果你是这种类型的车辆，称为装载拖运装置或铲子电车
situations. Here is a type of vehicle called a load haul dump unit or a scoop tram if you
来自加拿大。它用于在地下矿井中运输矿石。曾几何时
come from Canada. And it's used to carry ore in an underground mine. Now once upon a time
这些机器都是由坐在这里的司机驾驶的。问题是这些机器
these machines were all driven by a driver who sat here. The problem is that these machines
进入矿井的危险区域。所以一些矿业公司现在做的就是去除
go in to dangerous parts of the mine. So what some mining companies do now is to remove
操作员到安全的远程位置。
the operator to a safe remote location.
在这里，操作员可以使用操纵杆控制机器，并且可以看到状态
Here the operator is able to control the machine with the joystick and she can see the status
通过相机的视图和车辆的位置叠加的机器
of the machine through a view of the camera and the position of the vehicle superimpose
在我的地图上。而那种态势感知信息来自各种各样的
on a map of the mine. And that situational awareness information is coming from various
适合机器的感官。
senses fitted to the machine.
所以我们现在看到的是做工作的人和工作地点之间的分离
So what we're seeing now is a separation between the person doing the work and the place where
工作正在进行中。在许多其他情况下也会发生这种情况。水下
the work is occurring. And this happens in many other situations as well. An underwater
在海底深处做一些任务的车辆。操作员很舒服
vehicle which is doing some task deep beneath the ocean. The operator is at some comfortable
船上的工作站。考虑一下火星机器人的情况。它正在做这项工作
workstation on board a ship. Consider the case of a Mars robot. It's doing the work
地球科学家和化学家在火星表面，而实际的地质学家和化学家
of geologist and chemist on the surface of Mars whereas the actual geologist and chemist
坐在地球上的工作站。
are sitting at workstations on earth.
考虑一下我们之前看到的机器人手术的情况。外科医生正在做
Consider the case of robotic surgery that we look at earlier. The surgeons are doing
他们在工作站的工作在图片左侧的实际工作中，
their work at workstations on the left hand side of the picture where the actual work,
实际手术发生在患者体内。那就是
the actual surgery is occurring inside of the body of the patient. And that's being
由机器人完成。现在机器人通过电缆连接到工作站。所以
done by the robots here. Now the robots are connected to the workstations by cables. So
事实上没有理由说这些电缆不能再长一些了。事实上他们可能是
there's no reason in fact that those cables couldn't be longer. They could in fact be
洲际电信链接。这实际上是在证明。我们已经
an intercontinental telecommunications link. And this is actually being demonstrated. We've
让一个大陆的外科医生对另一个大陆的病人进行手术。
had surgeons on one continent performing an operation on a patient in another continent.
所以工人和工作地点现在非常明显。
So the worker and the place of work are now quite distinct.
传统上，工作一直在工作场所。工人一直在机器上
So traditionally, the work has been at the workplace. The worker has been on the machine
或直接控制机器。现在有了遥控技术，这是可能的
or controlling the machine directly. Right now with remote control technology, it's possible
工人可以远离机器。但是在未来我想会发生什么
that the worker can be remote from the machine. But in the future I think what's going to
碰巧的是，机器将更加智能，他们将能够自己完成大量的工作。
happen is that the machine will be smarter and they'll be able to a lot of the work all by themselves.
因此，我们将转向一个工人将远程管理许多机器的情况。那
So we will move to a situation where one worker will be remotely managing many machines. That
意味着那些不喜欢的工人坚持传统意义上的机器
means that the worker who is not joy sticking the machine in the traditional sense they
给机器一个高级命令。他们说机器A就这样做了
giving a high level command to the machine. They are saying machine A go off and do this
任务。机器B关闭并执行此任务。机器C去做这个任务。如果其中一台机器
task. Machine B go off and do this task. Machine C go and do this task. And if one of the machines
遇到问题然后它会回到运营商那里。
has encountered a problem then it would come back to the operator.
机器B可能会回到操作员那里说：“我不知道怎么做这件事
Machine B may come back to the operator and say, "I don't know how to do this thing that
你已经让我这么做了。“因此，操作员可以给机器B一些更详细的说明。
you've asked me to do." So the operator can give machine B some more detailed instructions.
所以这就像人类经理管理一些人类工作者的方式。但现在我们有了
So it's like the way a human manager manages a number of human workers. But now we have
管理一些智能机器的人力资源经理。
a human manager managing a number of intelligent machines.
也许在中期的某个时候，机器将足够聪明，不需要
Perhaps sometime in the medium future, the machines will be smart enough not to need
人事经理。但是现在我们需要人类直觉，智慧和经验的结合
human managers. But right now we need a combination of human intuition, intelligence and experience
结合不懈的职业道德，机器人工人的不知疲倦和可靠性。
combined with the relentless work ethic, the tirelessness and the reliability of robotic workers.
因此，在未来，我相信工作将成为人类管理者和机器人之间的合作伙伴关系
So in the future I believe work will be a partnership between human managers and robot
工作人员。而这可能会带来相同或更高水平的生产力
workers. And what this enables is the same or greater level of productivity perhaps with
降低操作员技能水平。因为技能将被封装在机器人工作者中。
lower operator skill levels. Because the skill is going to be encapsulated in the robot worker.
机器人工作人员将进行详细的熟练工作，人力资源经理将继续
The robot worker is going to do the detailed skilful work and the human manager is going
告诉机器人应该在哪里部署其特定技能。
to tell the robot where it should be deploying its particular skill.
机器将受到更少的损害，因为它们将由计算机驱动
Machines are going to suffer much less damage because they're going to be driven by computers
而不是人类。计算机将确保机器
rather than by human beings. The computers are going to ensure that the machines are
在他们的操作信封内安全驾驶。
driven safely and within their operational envelopes.
最后，我们将能够实现力量倍增。这意味着更多的工作
And finally we'll be able to achieve force multiplication. That means that more work
将能够由更少的人完成，因为他们将得到机器人的协助。
will be able to be done by fewer people because they're going to be assisted by robots.
为了实现这一目标，我们需要在哪里之间需要高通信带宽
In order to achieve this, we're going to need high communications bandwidth between where
机器人正在做他们的工作，人类经理正坐在他们的工作站。
the robots are doing their work and where the human managers are sitting at their workstations.
我们需要机器具有一定程度的本地自治权，某种程度的本地自动化。
We're going to need the machines to have some level of local autonomy, some level of local automation.
我们将不得不采用系统方法来完成我们的任务;我们在哪里定位
We're going to have to take a system's approach to the way we do task; where do we situate
人们，我们在哪里定位机器人，我们应该将多少智能嵌入到机器人中
the people, where do we situate the robot, how much intelligence should we embed in the
机器人，我们需要多少通讯。所以它将成为一种新的思维方式
robot, how much communications do we need. So it's going to be a new way of thinking
关于工作场所以及人类和机器人如何相互作用。
about work places and how humans and robots interact.